《やられた～!!
＜新八:謎の宇宙人に
ｷｬﾄﾙﾐｭｰﾃｨﾚｰｼｮﾝされ➡
(銀時)ぱっつぁんよ…➡
[Note: Playstation-like logo.]
銀さんの ｱﾅﾛｸﾞｽﾃｨｯｸが
やられた～!!》
＜彼らは 体を取り戻すべく➡
宇宙人の 唯一の手がかりである➡
体の一部を ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰに改造された
万事屋一行＞
宇宙人って…
殺しても 罪にならないよね？
♪♪～
MONKEY HUNTERという ﾈｯﾄｹﾞｰﾑを
開始｡
The curtain is about to rise...
途中 同じ目的をもつﾌﾟﾚｲﾔｰ 桂…➡
近藤… さっちゃん…➡
長谷川をﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰに加えた｡
A spectacular battle for survival.
そして ついに➡
件の宇宙人らしきﾌﾟﾚｲﾔｰに
肉迫するも 彼らの正体は…＞
A hunter trusts only...
Himself.
Beat them down...
Or dazzle them with your technique.
♪♪～
Monkey Hunter online!
[Note: Parody of Monster Hunter online TV spot.]
Risk your life to hunt them down!
The Odd Jobs were subjected
to alien abduction
by mysterious aliens from
outer space and
had parts of their bodies modified
into screwdrivers.
Patsuan, it's not a crime to kill
aliens from outer space, right?
They did it to him! They messed
with Gin-san's analog stick!
In order to restore their bodies,
they began playing an online
game called Monkey Hunter.
Along the way, other players
who sought their same goal
-Katsura, Kondo, Sachan, and
Hasegawa-joined their party.
Finally, they closed in on players who looked
like the aliens they were searching for...
They revealed themselves to be...
Look, I didn't say anything
earlier, but that's enough.
You guys have been sneaking
about trying to check us out.
What're you up to? Are you with them?
Huh? What're you saying?
I'm asking who you people are!
You should identify yourselves first
before asking us questions.
Huh? We are...
[Senpai]
Gun User
[Kohai]
[Whip User]
We are screwdrivers.
[Gintoki and his friends couldn't find a
single clue about the alien gamers.]
[Their fight to restore their bodies
finally comes to a conclusion!]
[JuuJuu En]
[Note: Parody of Korean BBQ
restaurant, JyoJyoEn.]
♪♪～
すいやせ～ん
ﾀﾝ塩 ２人前！
Excuse me.
Two orders of salted beef tongue
and four draft beers!
生ﾋﾞｰﾙ ４つ！
はい ただいま～！
Coming right up!
お客様～！
Everyone...have you decided
on your orders?
ご注文 お決まりに
なられましたでしょうか？
(みんな)ｶﾙﾋﾞ焼肉Ｇ 10人前で｡
Ten orders of Kalbi G.
[Note: Parody of Well-done steak G from Monster
Hunter. Kalbi is Korean style beef ribs.]
["Always Keep a Screwdriver In Your Heart"]
ちょっと 皆さん！
Come on, everybody!
何かしゃべってくださいよ！
せっかくのｵﾌ会なんだから！
Say something! This is
our offline meeting.
ｵﾌ会っつうか…
ほとんど知ってるﾔﾂなんだけど｡
Offline meeting? These
are all people I know.
見慣れたﾊﾞｶ面しかねえんだけど｡
The same stupid faces.
ｵﾌ会なんて
やってる場合じゃねえだろう!!
This is no time to be having
an offline meeting!
もう ３週目 突入してんだよ～!!
We're already into our third week!
３週だよ ３週！
Three weeks, dammit. Three weeks!
なんで３週間も こんな
くだらねえことやってんだよ！
Why are we doing such stupid
things three weeks in a row?
つうか ３週間やって まったく➡
We've been doing this for three weeks
and our predicament hasn't
gotten any better.
事態が好転してねえんだよ！
むしろ 悪化してんだよ！
In fact, it's gotten worse.
なんだったの!?
ｵﾚたちがやってきた狩りは！
What was the purpose of going
on the hunt in the first place?
２週に亘る狩りで ｵﾚたちは
いったい 何を得たの～!?
What did we gain from
two weeks of hunting?!
(近藤)まぁまぁ…｡
Now, now.
While it's true we didn't get any useful
information on the alien gamers,
確かに ｹﾞｰﾏｰ星人の有力な情報を
得ることはできなかった…｡
Mon-Hun brought us-comrades, who
share the same objective-together.
しかし
ﾓﾝﾊﾝは こうして ｵﾚたちを…➡
同じ目的をもった仲間を
引き寄せてくれたではないか｡
This is a prize more precious than any
rare item obtained from the hunt.
これこそが どんな ﾚｱ素材よりも
貴重な狩りの収穫さ｡
You call us "comrades," but this assembly
of fools are all hopeless cases.
仲間って お前…
こんな ﾊﾞｶばっか集まっても➡
箸にも棒にも かからねえんだよ！
What did you just say?!
(土方)なんだと ﾃﾒｴ！
土方く～ん！
Hijikata-kun, look at yourself in a mirror.
ｷﾐ 今の自分の姿 鏡で見てみ～！
ﾊﾞｶが映ってるから 見てみ～!!
There's a fool staring back at you!
(土方)ﾁﾝｺ ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰに改造された
ﾊﾞｶよりﾏｼじゃ ﾎﾞｹ！
I'm better off than a guy who's dick got
turned into a screwdriver, nimrod!
ｱﾎか ﾎﾞｹ！ ﾁﾝｺも含めて➡
You're an idiot.
I'm better than a guy who's entire body-
including his dick-got turned
into a screwdriver. Idiot.
全身改造されたﾊﾞｶより
ﾏｼじゃ ﾎﾞｹ～！
Hey, hey, please calm down!
ちょっと ちょっと！
落ち着いてくださいよ！
とにかく ｵﾌ会は➡
This offline meeting is an opportunity
for us to discuss in person
今後のことも 相談するため
設けられた場なんです｡
what we're going to do from now own.
冷静に 仲よく話し合いましょう｡
Let's all just calm down and
have a peaceful talk.
ﾎﾞｸらのﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰは➡
Our party was ultimately never able to obtain
any information on the alien gamers.
結局 ｹﾞｰﾏｰ星人の情報を
何も得られなかったけど➡
土方さんたちは
どうだったんですか？
Hijikata-san, how did you do?
つうか ﾃﾒｴら！ なんであんな
紛らわしい格好してたんだよ！
Why were the two of you using
such confusing avatars?
ﾃﾒｴらのせいでな 完全に
１週分 ﾑﾀﾞになったんだよ！
Because of you, we wasted
an entire week.
自分と同じ格好で
ｹﾞｰﾑ内 うろついてるﾌﾟﾚｲﾔｰが➡
No one wants to play inside a game
looking like himself, right?
気にかからんﾔﾂはいねえだろう？
あれは ﾔﾂらを釣るための
ｴｻだったんだよ｡
We did that to lure those aliens to us.
まさか ﾃﾒｴらみてえな➡
We never imagined we'd catch people
we didn't give a damn about...like you.
どうでもいいのが釣れるとは
思ってもいなかったが…｡
(沖田)土方さん…
そうでもありやせんぜ｡
Hijikata-san, that's not entirely true.
(沖田)あの釣り…
案外 小魚を追って➡
We might have been fishing for guppies
and unexpectedly hooked a big fish.
思わぬ大魚が釣れたかも…｡
(桂)あっ… 遅れてすいません｡
Sorry I'm late.
(桂)どうも｡
ﾌﾙｰﾂﾎﾟﾝﾁ侍 Ｇで～す！
I'm Fruit Punch Samurai G.
ｼｬﾊﾞ最後のﾒｼだ｡ 何が食いたい？
This is your last meal as a free
man. What would you like?
じゃあ 上ﾐﾉで｡
I'll have the prime tripe.
Excuse me. One order
of Tainted raw meat.
[Note: Parody of Tainted meat
from Monster Hunter.]
すいやせ～ん！
ｺｲﾂに しびれ生肉 追加～！
♪♪～
(沖田)おら 食え！
Okay, eat up.
ﾊ… ﾊﾒられた～！
You tricked me! I never expected
the offline meeting to be a trap!
まさか ｵﾌ会が罠だったとは…！
You're an idiot!
ﾊﾞｶだろ？ ｵﾒｴ｡ なんで 攘夷志士が
ｵﾌ会に参加してんだよ｡
What's an Anti-Foreigner Faction samurai
doing at an offline meeting?
(桂)攘夷志士だってな➡
There are times when even an Anti-Foreigner
Faction samurai needs some time off!
たまには
ｵﾌになりたいときもあらぁ！
When he wants to forget everything
and have a good time!
(桂)すべてを忘れて
はしゃぎたいときもあらぁ！
Your brain is constantly "off."
お前はずっと 頭の中 ｵﾌだろ？
Your adapter was pulled
from its socket years ago.
ｱﾀﾞﾌﾟﾀが ｺﾝｾﾝﾄから外れてるだろ？
(桂)ﾌﾝ！ ﾊﾞｶ者どもが！
Hmph. You fools.
Nothing good will come
from capturing me.
(桂)ｵﾚを捕まえたところで
何も事態は好転せんぞ｡
It doesn't change the fact that
you're all screwdrivers.
お前たちが ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰであるという
事実は 何も変わらん｡
You're a screwdriver, too, aren't you?
(沖田)つうか お前も ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰだろ｡
(桂)それどころか お前たちは➡
No only that, you'll miss a chance
to obtain valuable information.
貴重な情報を得る機会も
失うことになるのだぞ｡
桂！ まさか ｷｻﾏ
何か新しい情報を…！
Katsura, don't tell me; you
have new information?
さあな…｡
人にものを尋ねるときは➡
I might.
When you ask someone for something you
should show the appropriate courtesy.
それなりの礼儀というものが
あるだろう…｡
Kondo-san, don't fall for his tricks.
近藤さん…
ｺｲﾂの手にのっちゃいけねえぜ｡
どうせ 逃げたいばかりに
でまかせ言ってるのに 違えねえ｡
He's probably making it
up to try and escape.
Look at this before you doubt me.
疑うなら
まずは これを見てみるがいい｡
二度と 同じ口は
利けなくなるだろう｡
You'll never talk that
way about me again.
This is...?!
こ… これは…!?
[Drivers Wanted Now]
おっと…
見せられるのは ここまでだ｡
Oops, that's all I can show you.
(桂)連絡先 面接会場が
知りたければ➡
Get me the Prime tripe if you want
to know the contact number
and interview location.
まずは 上ﾐﾉを出してもらおう｡
(神楽)ほちゃ～!!
うぉ～っ!!
One Prime tripe!
(神楽)上ﾐﾉ 一丁!!
ぐはっ！
One kalbi!
ｶﾙﾋﾞ 一丁!!
なに ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰとして➡
Why are you showing
us a truck driver ad?!
生きる決意 固めてんだ～!!
That's totally the wrong kind of driver!
つうか 完全にﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰ違いだろう！
Where's the info on the
alien gamers, nimrod?!
ｹﾞｰﾏｰ星人の情報は どうしたんだ
ﾎﾞｹ～!!
そんなものは
あるわけがあるまい…｡
I wouldn't have anything like that.
この期に及んで まだ現実から
目をそらそうというのか？
Are you still going to ignore reality?
(桂)ｷｻﾏらも うすうすと
感づき始めているはず｡
You all must've realized that if we haven't found
any information about the alien gamers by now,
we're not ever going to find any.
もはや 何の情報も 何の手段も
ありはしない！
ｹﾞｰﾏｰ星人を捕まえることは➡
There's nothing more we can do.
もう不可能だということを！
(土方)ﾊﾞｶ言ってんじゃねえよ｡
Don't be ridiculous. We're
not giving up so easily.
こんなことくらいで
諦められるか｡
That's right! We're going
to restore our bodies!
そうだ～！
ｵﾚたちは 元の体を取り戻す!!
(近藤)勝負は これから… あっ!!
The fight begins right now...
Ack!
近藤さん… これ…｡
Kondo-san...is this...
ﾈｼﾞ星の第三王女… ﾌﾟﾗｽ姫だ｡
She's the third princess of Planet
Screw...Princess Phillips.
実は 今 見合いの話が…｡
Actually, there's talk of an arranged
marriage meeting...
近藤さん… ｱﾝﾀ まさか!?
Kondo-san, you can't be serious!
我々に 今 必要なのは
ﾓﾝﾊﾝをやることでも➡
What we need to do now...
Is not play Mon-Hun or plan useless
strategies over barbeque.
焼き肉屋で
ﾑﾀﾞに策を論ずることでもない｡
ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰとして生きていく覚悟だ｡
We need to decide how we're
going to live as screwdrivers.
♪♪～
≪ありがとうございました～｡
Thank you very much.
＜ それから 誰一人として
口を開く者はなく➡
After that, no one spoke a word...
鬱々とした雰囲気のなか
ﾓﾝﾊﾝﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰは 解散した＞
and everyone left the Mon-Hun
party depressed.
＜ﾎﾞｸらは 気づかぬうちに
逃げていたのかもしれない｡
Perhaps without realizing
it, we were running away.
ｹﾞｰﾑでしか ﾔﾂらを
捕まえることはできない｡
The only way to catch the aliens
was through the game.
そう言いながら ﾎﾞｸらは ただ…➡
We kept reminding ourselves of that...
自分たちの置かれた
この つらい現実から➡
but perhaps all we were doing
was ignoring the harsh reality
目を背けたいばかりに➡
ｹﾞｰﾑという世界に気づかぬうちに➡
we were stuck in and escaping
into the game.
逃げ込んでいただけ
なのかもしれない＞
＜ｺﾝﾄﾛｰﾗｰを手放し
狩りを終えた今…➡
We gave up our online avatars,
and the hunt was over.
ﾎﾞｸらは 現実と
向き合わなければならなかった＞
Now we had to face reality.
(草野)本日未明
真選組により検挙された➡
Before dawn this morning, Kotaro Katsura,
a central figure among the
攘夷浪士の 中核的存在
桂 小太郎が➡
Anti-Foreigner Faction samurai, who had
been apprehended by the Shinsengumi,
収監中の大江戸刑務所より
脱獄したもようです｡
escaped from Oedo Prison, where
he had been incarcerated.
では 現場の結野ｱﾅに
伝えてもらいましょう｡
We have a report from the scene
by Ketsuno announcer.
結野ｱﾅ… 結野ｱﾅ…！
Ketsuno? Ketsuno, are you there?
(結野ｱﾅ)はい！ 現場の結野です｡
Yes. This is Ketsuno reporting
from the scene.
(結野ｱﾅ)監獄から脱獄した
攘夷浪士 桂 小太郎…｡
Anti-Foreigner Faction samurai, Kotaro
Katsura, has escaped from prison.
He escaped in just a week.
Zura's pretty good.
たった一週間で 早くも脱獄か…
ﾂﾞﾗもやるｱﾙな｡
Just how did he escape from a
maximum security prison cell?
ああ… 真選組も 要が
いなくなっちゃったから➡
Yeah. The Shinsengumi's
missing its key members,
Here at the site of the first-ever
escape of this type...
抑え込むことも
できなかったんだろうねぇ｡
so they couldn't keep him locked up.
お～い ｵﾒｴら… そろそろ行くぜ｡
Hey you guys, it's time to go.
は～い｡
Coming.
♪♪～
[Mover Jobs Gin]
ﾓﾝﾊﾝﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰのみんな 今 どこで
何やってるんでしょうね？
I wonder what everyone who came to
the Mon-Hun party is doing right now?
さぁな…｡
Who knows...
みんな どっかで
ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰやってんじゃねえの？
They're all probably working
as drivers somewhere.
＜ そう言った 銀さんの横顔は
少し 寂しげに見えた｡
As he said that, Gin-san looked a bit sad.
ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰとしての新しい生活は
思いのほか充実していた｡
Our new lives as drivers
was surprising fulfilling.
仕事は きつかったが
万事屋をしていた頃より➡
The work was hard, but our income was way
more than we ever made as Odd Jobs.
ﾎﾞｸらの収入は 増えた｡
でも 銀さんの顔は 晴れない＞
But Gin-san never seemed happy.
♪♪～
[Gaki Private Housing Contractor]
おい 土方…➡
Hey, Hijikata, give me a screwdriver.
ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰ｡
へい！
Right!
No, not one that big. Just
a normal-sized one.
そんな でけえんじゃなくて
普通の！
へい！
Right.
It was really bringing the
whole gang down.
＜本当に これで
よかったのだろうか？＞
ﾁｪｽﾄｰ！
≪ﾅｲｽｼｮｯﾄ！
Chesuto!
[Note: Southern Kyushu samurai battle cry.]
Nice shot!
いやぁ…｡
＜ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰとしての自分を享受し➡
We realized we were stuck being
drivers and so lived as drivers.
ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰとして
生きていくということ＞
おい ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰ！
Hey, driver.
へい｡
いや そのﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰじゃなくて➡
Right here.
No, not that kind of driver.
A wooden one.
１番ｳｯﾄﾞ｡
へい｡
Right.
＜ それが 本当に 現実を見てる
ってことなのかな？
Were we really
facing reality?
こんなんじゃ ﾎﾞｸら…＞
At this rate, we'll be...
(近藤)ええっ！
ひょっとして 姫って ﾌﾟﾗｽﾈｼﾞ～!?
What? Princess, might you
be a Phillips screw?
おお 奇遇ですね～ 実は ﾎﾞｸ
ﾌﾟﾗｽﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰなんですよ！
What a coincidence! I'm
a Phillips screwdriver!
(松平)ようよう お二人さん！
Good for you two!
ひょっとして 運命の赤いﾈｼﾞで
締めつけられてんじゃねえの？
Perhaps you two are held together
by the red screw of destiny!
[Note: Parody of Japanese saying that two people are
held together by a red thread/destined to be together.]
(２人)ﾀﾞｰｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ!!
Life seemed so much more real when
we were playing the game.
＜ｹﾞｰﾑをやってた頃のほうが
よっぽど…＞
[However, here's one woman
who hasn't given up yet.]
(さっちゃん)冗談じゃないわよ！
No way! It might be okay if I had been modified
into a screw that fit only Gin-san,
私が 銀さん専用のﾈｼﾞに
改造されたなら構わないけど➡
こんな状態
耐えられるわけないわ！
but this is unbearable!
♪♪～
If our lives keep going on like this...
＜ こうして 時は流れていき➡
当たり前のように
心のもやもやは➡
will it become the norm and will
the cloud over our hearts fade?
薄まっていくのだろうか？＞
♪♪～
[Men's Dreams]
＜割り切れない… この
どこか諦めに似た脱力感は…＞
What is this listless feeling?
Like we've given up without
knowing why?
♪♪～
Your screwdriver.
ｽｸﾘｭｰﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰでございます｡
♪♪～
うわっ！
＜ いつか心から洗い流される日は
来るのだろうか？＞
Will there come a day when the cloud
is washed from our hearts?
♪♪～
Is our hunt really over...?
＜ﾎﾞｸらの狩りは 本当にもう…＞
♪♪～
[Y-You're...]
あっ ﾋｯﾁﾊｲｶｰだ｡ 銀さん
乗せてってあげましょうよ｡
It's a hitchhiker.
Gin-san, let's give her a lift.
あれ？
That was someone we know.
知ってる 顔だったんですけど…｡
仕事中だ｡ 知るか…｡
I'm working. I don't care.
Take me to the GEO Kabukicho
Branch. That's our destination.
[Note: GEO is a Japanese
rental video & game store.]
(さっちゃん)げお かぶき町支店
駐車場まで｡
そこが私たちの目的地｡
ｷﾞｬｰ!!
ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰになっても Ｓなのね
Ｓﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰなんてあったかしら｡
You're still an "S" (sadist) even as a driver.
Was there ever such a
thing as an S-driver?
♪♪～
仕事中だ 帰れ｡
I'm working. Go home.
ずいぶんと
仕事熱心になったじゃない！
You sure are earnest about your work.
Is this how you plan on
playing the realist-
そうやって
自分の運命を受け入れて➡
accepting your fate, enduring
it, and working at it?!
耐えて従事して
ﾘｱﾘｽﾄでも気取ってるつもり!?
Is this how you really want
to live your life?!
それで現実を生きてるつもり!?
(さっちゃん)そんなんじゃ
決められたﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑの中で➡
Then you're exactly the same
as those alien gamers,
決められたｼﾅﾘｵこなして
生きた気になってる➡
holed up in their tissue-filled
room thinking they're alive
because they spend all their
time playing a videogame.
部屋じゅう ﾃｨｯｼｭだらけの
ｹﾞｰﾏｰ星人と同じよ！
本当に現実を生きたいなら➡
If you really want to live
in reality...then fight it!
現実と戦いなさいよ！
Create your own destiny and
live in your own reality!
自分の運命を切り開いて
自分で現実を創りだしなさいよ！
Isn't that what it truly means to live?
(さっちゃん)それが本当の意味で
生きるってことでしょ！
(さっちゃん)それが人生をﾌﾟﾚｲする
真のｹﾞｰﾏｰ 坂田 銀時でしょ!!
Isn't that a true gamer?
One who plays the game of life-
isn't that who Gintoki Sakata is?!
(さっちゃん)たとえ 負けたって
私は気にしないから｡
I don't care if you lose!
I don't care if you remain
a screwdriver! Because...
ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰのままだって
私は気にしないから！ だって➡
Because...my nipples are...
だって 私も乳首…｡
やかましいﾒｽﾌﾞﾀだぜ｡
銀さん…｡
That was one noisy sow.
Gin-san...
ぱっつぁん 地図だせ
案内頼む｡
Patsuan, the map. Show me the way.
The real hunt begins now!
こっからが 本物の
狩りの始まりじゃ!!
[GEO KABUKICHO BRANCH]
＜ﾎﾞｸらの狩りは…＞
Our hunt...
(先輩)いやぁ もうね
買った 買った｡
We sure bought a lot.
＜ まだ…＞
...was still...
With all this, I think we
can leave Earth happy.
これで ｵﾒｴ
地球に思い残すことはないな｡
We bought too many games.
(後輩)買いすぎっすよ ｹﾞｰﾑ｡
(先輩)よし 出発｡
Okay, time to take off...
＜終わってはいなかった＞
うおおぉっ!!
...not over.
Senpai, there's a strange vehicle!
せ 先輩！ おかしな車が！
It's headed straight for us!
(後輩)ｵﾚたちの船にむかって
突っ込んできます！
What? Take off. C'mon, fly.
え!? 早く 飛べ飛べ！
早く飛べ！
はい！
Right.
(後輩)船が全然 浮上しない｡
The ship's not lifting off.
Senpai, there's an intruder
in propulsion room four.
せ 先輩！
第四動力室に侵入者が！
What is it? What's going on?
え？ 何なの 何なの？
Those are...
あ あれは!!
(桂/近藤)うおおぉっ!!
(後輩)ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰ！ 巨大なﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰが➡
screwdrivers! Massive screwdrivers
are drilling into the propulsion unit.
動力部のﾈｼﾞを
外している!!
Katsura!
(近藤)桂!!
(桂)やめろ！
Stop it! Don't call me by that
name right now! Kondo.
(桂)今は その名で呼ぶな 近藤！
(近藤)やめろ！
Stop it! Don't call me by
that name right now!
(近藤)今は その名で呼ぶな！
Don't say anything!
何も言うな!!
(近藤)今のｵﾚは ただのﾊﾝﾀ-｡
Right now, I'm just a hunter!
Fruit Chinpo Samurai G!
I'm Fruit Punch Samurai G!
ﾌﾙｰﾂﾁﾝﾎﾟ侍Ｇだ！
ﾌﾙｰﾂﾎﾟﾝﾁ侍Ｇだ！
(後輩)先輩！
Senpai ...
The truck is coming straight for us.
車が 車が来ます！
Blast it. Ready cannons!
そんなもん 迎撃だ
砲門を出せ！
(先輩)ｾｰﾌﾃｨｰﾛｯｸ 解除
照準 狙え！
Safety lock off. Aiming.
はい 発射！
Okay, fire!
♪♪～
あとは頼まぁ｡
They're all yours.
ｳｿ～!!
This can't be!
♪♪～
You're insane!
(先輩)乱暴な…！
船を止めろ！
ｵﾚのﾁﾝｺを返せ！
Land this ship. Give me back my dick.
どういうつもりか知らんが
ｵﾒｴ➡
I don't know what you're after,
止められるもんなら
止めてみろ｡
but try and stop the ship if you can.
This ship won't stop no matter how
much you wreck the propulsion unit.
(先輩)どれだけ動力部を
分解したところで ｵﾒｴ➡
この船は止まらんぞ あん｡
あのﾒｲﾝﾌﾞﾚｲﾝを
分解せんことには➡
You see...
This ship will keep on flying unless
you disassemble the main brain.
この船は飛び続ける ｸｸｸ…｡
You can't do it with your screwdrivers.
(先輩)お前たちの そのﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰでは
ﾑﾘな話だがな ん？
あのﾈｼﾞは ｵﾒｴ
特殊なﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰでなければ➡
That screw can't be turned without
a special screwdriver.
開けることはできんよ ん？
You've lost...
お前たちの負け…｡
そうかい｡
Is that so?
どこで使えば
いいのかと思ったら…➡
I was wondering where I could
use this...I guess this is it.
こんなところに｡
Wh...What?
なんだと!?
♪♪～
(先輩)ｷｻﾏ！ まさかそれは!!
You... It can't be...!
そのﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰは!!
That screwdriver is...!
Fade in!
[Note: Parody of anime "Brave Raideen."]
ﾌｪｰﾄﾞｲﾝ!!
Go to hell!
くだばりやがれ!!
♪♪～
え？ ｵﾚたちの身体は？
Huh? What about our bodies?
You did well to come this far.
I am the Masta Bayter, the
Emperor of Darkness.
(ﾏｽｶｰｸ)余が ｷｻﾏを狩るか
ｷｻﾏが 余を狩るか➡
Will I hunt you down, or
will you hunt me down?
最後の勝負といこう｡
Let's have our final battle.
(Ｍ)うおおぉっ!!
《長谷川:待っていろ みんな
今すぐに行く!!》
Wait for me everyone. I'll be right there!
[The End]
(ｾﾐの鳴き声)
[GinTama - Memories of Summer Vacation]
ｾﾐってかわいそうｱﾙ｡
I feel sorry for cicadas.
They spend years in the ground,
何年も土の中で過ごして
ようやく 地上に出て➡
but when they can finally come
out, they die in just a week.
これからだと思ったら
１週間で死んじゃうなんて｡
Don't feel sorry for them.
んなことねえよ｡
なんで 外に出てからが
本番だと思ってんの｡
What makes you think their life begins
after they come out of the ground?
ｱｲﾂらにとっては 土の中が
本番かもしれねえだろ？
For cicadas, the time spent underground
might be their real lifetime.
毎日 土の中で
寿司 食ってるかもしんねえだろ｡
They might be having sushi
underground every day.
外に出るときは もう
人生終わってんだよ｡
By the time they come
out, their life is over.
余生だよ 余生｡
It's just the last part of their life.
ｹﾞｰﾄﾎﾞｰﾙでも
してくっかくらいの感じで➡
They come out looking forward
to playing gateball.
[Note: Gateball is a croquet-like game
associated with old folks in Japan.]
地上に出てくんだよ ｱｲﾂら｡
(神楽)ﾏｼﾞｱﾙか 毎日寿司ｱﾙか｡
Are you serious? Sushi everyday?
That makes me angry.
(神楽)なんか ﾑｶついてきたｱﾙ｡
ﾑｶつくだろ？
Doesn't it, though?
We eat raw egg and soy sauce on rice
everyday-we're a lot more pitiful.
毎日 卵かけご飯のｵﾚたちのほうが
よっぽど かわいそうだよ｡
I feel sorry for mosquitoes.
蚊ってかわいそうｱﾙ｡
They only want blood to feed the
babies inside their bodies,
お腹の子のために
血がほしいだけなのに➡
吸血鬼扱いされて
潰されちゃうなんて｡
but we treat them like vampires
and squash them.
Don't feel sorry for them.
んなことねえよ｡
Don't you know why you feel itchy
when a mosquito bites you?
お前 なんで蚊に刺されたら
かゆくなるか知らねえの｡
あれ お前 唾液のせいらしいぜ｡
It's because of its saliva.
血 吸うのと同時にﾔﾂら 唾液を
人の体に送り込んでんだよ｡
As it sucks your blood, it pumps
saliva into your body.
人んちで ご飯ごちそうになって➡
They get treated to a meal at your house
and spit on you as they leave.
つば吐きかけて
帰ってくんだよ ｱｲﾂら｡
(蚊)ﾍﾟｯ ｸｿまずいﾒｼ
ありがとうござんした！
Thanks for the god-awful meal.
(神楽)ﾏｼﾞｱﾙか
なんか ﾑｶついてきたｱﾙ｡
Are you serious? That makes me angry.
Of course it does.
ﾑｶつくだろ わかったら
蚊取り線香 とってこい｡
Now that you know that,
get the mosquito coil.
うっ… くっ…｡
(神楽)ﾏﾀﾞｵってかわいそうｱﾙ｡
I feel sorry for Madao.
そうだね｡
(長谷川)なんか言えば!?
I do, too.
Aren't you going to say something?
[The End]
[Preview]
Gin-san! It happened!
Next time, Otsu-chan makes the first appearance
she's had in a while with her new song!
Are you sure it's okay?
There hasn't been a single song of
hers that hasn't caused trouble.
The next episode... "When Nagging Goes
Too Far It Becomes Intimidating."
[Otsu gets into an accident immediately
after releasing her new song!]
[Her producer, Tsunpo, is injured, too. Who
is responsible? What will Otsu do?!]
[See you next time.]